今天的论文，我要讨论这个鸡蛋花，这是一个相当老的
today the paper I'm going to discuss
this frangipani this is a fairly old
分布式文件系统文件之所以读取它的原因是因为它
distributed file system paper the reason
why were reading it though is because it
与缓存一致性和
has a lot of interesting and good design
having to do with cache coherence and
分布式事务和分布式崩溃恢复以及
distributed transactions and distributed
crash recovery as well as the
他们之间的互动，那才是真正的想法
interactions between them so those are
those are the really the ideas behind
这是我们要尝试挑出来的，所以这真的是我们很多
this that we're gonna try to tease out
so these are it's really a lot of our
缓存一致性是我是否有缓存的想法
caching coherence is really the idea of
if I have something cached that
但是，即使我有缓存，如果您修改它，您也会知道
nevertheless if you modify it despite me
having a cache you know something will
发生，以便我可以看到您的修改，我们也有
happen so I can see your your
modifications and we also have
将其内部需要的操作分发给文件系统，以便能够
distributed its actions which are needed
internally to file systems to be able to
对文件系统的数据结构进行复杂的更新，因为文件
make complex updates to the file system
data structures and because the file
系统本质上是由一堆服务器拆分而成的
system is essentially split up among a
bunch of servers it's critical to be
能够从崩溃中恢复，那些服务器的整体设计成为了朋友
able to recover from crashes and those
servers the overall design a friend
pammi这是一个旨在查找现有文件的网络文件系统
pammi it's a network file system it's
intended to look to existing
旨在与UNIX等现有应用程序一起使用的应用程序
applications this is intended to work
with existing applications like UNIX
我们在人的工作站上运行的普通UNIX程序
programs ordinary UNIX programs we're
running on people's workstations much
像Athena的AFS一样，您可以在Athena主目录中找到各种
like Athena's AFS lets you get at your
Athena home directory and various
任何Athena工作站的项目目录，总的来说
project directories from any Athena
workstation so the kind of overall
图片是您有一堆用户，论文世界中的每个用户都是
picture is that you have a bunch of
users each user in the papers world is
坐在工作站前面，你知道那不是笔记本电脑吗
sitting in front of a workstation which
is you know real not a laptop in those
天，但有点像带键盘和鼠标显示的计算机，
days but sort of computer with a
keyboard and display in a mouse and
Windows系统，所以每个人都坐着
Windows system at all so each one is
sitting
在计算机工作站的前面，我要称呼您知道的工作站
front of a computer workstation I'm
gonna call the workstations you know
工作站每个工作站再运行一个工作站
workstation one more station to each
workstation runs an instance of the
素馨花服务器，我的意思是说，你知道的几乎所有
frangipani server I meant so a huge
amount of the you know almost all of the
这篇论文中发生的事情在每个鸡蛋夹软件中都有
stuff that happens in this paper goes on
in the frangipani software in each
工作站，所以也许他们坐在工作站前面，
workstation so maybe they're sitting in
front of a workstation and they might be
运行普通程序，例如读取和写入文件的文本编辑器
running ordinary programs like a text
editor that's reading and writing files
也许当他们完成源文件的编辑后，他们会通过
and maybe when they finished editing a
source file they run it through the
这些普通程序制作文件时，Reiser源文件的编译器
compiler that the Reiser source file
when these ordinary programs make file
内核中有一个系统调用，其中有一个素馨花模块，该模块实现了
system calls inside the kernel there's a
frangipani module that implements the
所有这些工作站内部的文件系统互相复制，然后
file system inside of all of these
workstations each other on copy and then
文件系统数据结构的真实存储，例如文件
the real storage of the file system data
structures things like certainly file
内容，还有I节点和目录以及alissa文件，以及每个
contents but also I nodes and
directories and alissa file and each
目录以及有关我所知道的信息和哪些块是免费的信息
directory and the information about what
I knows and what blocks are free all
存储在称为花瓣的共享虚拟磁盘表面中，它位于单独的
that's stored in a shared virtual disk
surface called petal it's on a separate
您知道的一组计算机可能是服务器计算机和一台计算机
set of machines that are you know
probably server machines and a machine
房间，而不是人们桌子上的工作站
room rather than workstations on
people's desks pedal among many other
东西会复制数据，因此您可以想到踏板服务器即将问世
things replicates data so you can sort
of think of pedal servers is coming in
对和一次崩溃，我们仍然可以获取我们的数据，因此当素馨花时
pairs and one crashes we can still get
at our data and so when frangipani
需要读取或写入一个您知道读取的目录或它发送远程内容的东西
needs to read or write a you know read a
directory or something it sends a remote
程序调用正确的踏板服务器说得好，这是
procedure call off to the correct pedal
server to say well here's the block that
我需要您知道，请为我阅读，然后将其退还给
I need you know please read it for me
please return that block and for the
花瓣的大部分部分就像磁盘驱动器，您可以将其视为一种
most part petal is acting like a disk
drive you can think of it as a kind of
作为一个共享磁盘驱动器共享，所有这些素馨花素的膝盖都在与之交谈，
shared as a shared disk drive that all
these frangipane knees talk to and it's
称为虚拟磁盘
called a virtual disk
从我们的角度来看，对于大多数讨论，我们只是想像
from our point of view for most of this
discussion we're just going to imagine
踏板只是磁盘驱动器，所有这些都通过网络使用
pedal is just being a disk ride that's
used over the network by all these
Handy's的朋友，所以您可以给它一个方块来读写
friends of Handy's and so it has you
read and write it by giving it a block
磁盘上的数字或地址，似乎我想读取该块
number or an address on the disk and
seem like I'd like to read that block
就像普通的硬盘一样，所以该文件的预期用途是
just like an ordinary hard drive okay so
the intended use for this file so the
作者打算使用的用途实际上是
use that the authors intended is
actually reasonably important driver in
设计他们想要的是支持自己的活动以及
the design what they wanted was to
support their own activities and what
他们是某个研究实验室的成员，也许有50个人
they were were were members of a
research lab of maybe say 50 people in
这个研究实验室，他们习惯于共享基础设施，例如时间
this research lab and they were used to
shared infrastructure things like time
使用以前的网络文件系统共享机器或工作站以共享
sharing machines or workstations using
previous network file systems to share
合作研究人员之间的文件，所以他们都希望他们
files among cooperating groups of
researchers so they both wanted they
他们想要一个可以用来存储自己的主目录的文件系统
they wanted a file system that they
could use to store their own home
目录以及存储共享的项目文件，因此这意味着
directories in as well as storing shared
project files and so that meant that if
我编辑一个文件，我真的很希望其他人和我的其他人
I edit a file I'd really like the other
people my work and the other people I
可以读取我刚刚编辑的文件，因此我们希望
work with to be able to read the file I
just edited so we want that kind of
分享，此外，如果我能坐在我的任何工作站上也很棒
sharing and in addition it's great if I
can sit down at any workstation my
工作站您的工作站是库中的公共工作站，仍然可以
workstation your workstation a public
workstation in the library and still get
在我所有主目录的所有文件中
at all of the files of all my home
directory everything I need in my
环境，因此他们对人类用户的共享文件系统非常感兴趣
environment so they're really interested
in a shared file system for human users
在一个相对较小的组织中，规模很小，每个人都可以信任所有人
in a relatively small organization small
enough that everybody was trusted all
人们所有的计算机，所以实际上设计几乎没有什么可做的
the people all the computers so really
the design has essentially nothing to
说到安全性，实际上可以说在像这样的环境中是行不通的
say about security and indeed arguably
would not work in an environment like
雅典娜，您无法真正信任用户或工作站，因此
Athena where you can't really trust the
users or the workstations so it's really
就性能而言，非常适合其环境而设计
very much designed for their their
environment now as far as performance
他们的环境也很重要，你知道事实证明，
their environment was also important you
know it turns out that the way most
人们使用计算机是他们坐在前面的租赁工作站
people use computers are leased
workstations they sit in front of is
他们主要是读写自己的文件，并且可能会读取一些共享的文件
that they mostly read and write their
own files and they may read some shared
您知道程序或某些项目文件之类的文件，但大多数情况下
files you know programs or some project
files or something but most of the time
我正在读写文件，而您正在读写文件
I'm reading and writing my files and
you're reading and writing your files on
您的工作站，您知道这确实是我们积极参与的例外
your workstation and you know it's
really the exception that we're actively
共享文件，因此能够以一种方式或
sharing files so it makes a huge amount
of sense to be able to one way or
即使正式的文件的真实副本存储在此
another even though officially the real
copies of files are stored in this
共享磁盘，如果我们可以进行某种缓存，那就太棒了，因此
shared disk it's fantastic if we can
have some kind of caching so that after
我登录后将文件在本地缓存了一段时间，以便可以
I log in and I use my files for a while
they're locally cached here so they can
被弄到，你知道微秒而不是毫秒，如果
be gotten gotten that and you know
microseconds instead of milliseconds if
我们必须从文件服务器中获取它们，以便支持法国比利牛斯山脉
we have to fetch them from the file
servers ok so French Pyrenees supported
这种缓存还不仅支持右向缓存
this this kind of caching furthermore it
supported right-back caching not only
在每个工作站和每个素馨花服务器中缓存每个缓存
caching in each in each workstation and
each frangipani server we also have
右后缓存，这意味着如果我要修改某些内容，
right back caching which means that if I
want to modify something if I modify a
文件，甚至在目录中创建文件，或者删除文件或基本上
file or even create a file in a
directory or delete a file or basically
只要没有其他工作站不需要看的其他任何操作
do any other operation as long as nobody
else no other workstation needs to see
鸡蛋花与回写缓存一起使用
it
frangipani acts with a write back cache
这意味着如果我在以下位置创建文件，我的写操作将仅保留在缓存中本地
and that means that my writes stay only
local in the cache if I create a file at
至少最初有关新创建文件的信息表示新
least initially the information about
the newly created file said a newly
用初始化的内容分配了索引节点，并且您知道添加了新条目
allocated inode with initialized
contents and you know a new entry added
以新的名字对待我的主目录的所有这些修改
to a new name attitudes to my home
directory all those modifications
最初只是在缓存中完成，因此创建文件之类的事情
initially are just done in the cache and
therefore things like creating a file
可以非常快速地完成，他们只需要在此修改本地内存
can be done extremely rapidly they just
require modifying local memory in this
机器的磁盘缓存，它们通常不会写回去兜售，直到
machine's disk cache and they're not
written back in general to peddle until
之后，至少在最初，我们可以对文件进行各种修改
later so at least initially we can do
all kinds of modifications to the file
系统，至少到我自己的目录，我自己的文件完全在本地，这就是
system at least to my own directories my
own files completely locally and that's
对性能非常有帮助，就像您知道的千分之一
enormous ly helpful for performance it's
like a you know factor of a thousand
能够修改本地存储器中的内容与具有
difference being able to modify
something in local memory versus having
发送远程过程调用以立即发送服务器的一个严重后果是
to send a remote procedure calls to send
server now one serious consequence of
这是这里体系结构的绝对决定因素
that it's extremely determinative of the
architecture here is that that meant
文件系统的逻辑必须在每个工作站中才能使
that the logic of the file system has to
be in each workstation in order for my
工作站能够执行诸如创建文件等操作
workstation to be able to implement
things like create a file just operating
脱离其本地缓存，意味着文件的所有逻辑和所有智能
out of its local cache it means all the
logic all the intelligence for the file
系统必须坐在我的工作站及其设计中
system has to be sitting here in my
workstation and in their design
基本上与踏板共享存储系统知道的近似
basically to a first approximation the
pedal shared storage system knows
绝对没有关于文件系统或文件或目录的所有逻辑
absolutely nothing about file systems or
files or directories all that logic this
从某种意义上说，这是一个非常简单的简单系统，
is a very in a sense very
straightforward simple system and all
每位客户的素馨花都在这里，这是非常复杂的
the complexity is here in the frangipani
in each client so it's a very kind of
分散计划，原因之一是-因为那就是你
decentralized scheme and one of the
reasons is - because that's what you
真正需要的或这些是他们可以想到的设计，以允许他们做
really need or these that was a design
they could think of to allow them to do
纯粹在每个工作站本地进行修改，它确实具有不错的一面
modifications purely locally in each
workstation it does have the nice side
效果虽然我是因为大多数复杂性和大部分CPU时间
effect though that I'm since most of the
complexity and most of the CPU time
花费是在这里花费的，这意味着您在添加用户时将工作站添加到
spent is spent here it means that as you
add workstations as you add users to the
系统会自动获得更多的CPU容量来运行这些新用户文件
system you automatically get more CPU
capacity to run those new users file
系统操作，因为大多数文件系统操作仅发生在本地
system operations because most file
system operations happen just locally in
占用CPU时间最多的工作站是在这里，因此系统会
the workstation that's most of the CPU
time is spent here so the system does
每次添加工作站时，都具有一定程度的自然扩展可伸缩性
have a certain degree of natural scaling
scalability as you add workstations each
新的工作站给新用户带来了更多负担，但同时也带来了更多负担
new workstation is a bit more load from
a new user but it's also a bit more
用户运行文件系统的可用CPU时间
available CPU time to run that users
file system operations of course at some
点，您将在中央存储系统中用完所有气体，然后您
point you're gonna run out of gas here
in the central storage system and you
知道，那么您可能需要添加更多存储服务器
know then you may need to add more
storage servers to all right
好吧，所以我们有在这里进行认真缓存的系统，此外
so okay so we have the system that does
serious caching here and furthermore
在缓存中进行修改，实际上这些修改会立即
does the modifications in the cache that
actually these immediately to some
设计中的严峻挑战，而设计主要是要解决
serious challenges in the design and the
design is mostly about solving the
我要提出的挑战在很大程度上是
challenges I'm about to lay out these
are largely count challenges of that's
来自缓存和这种分散式架构，其中大多数
come from caching and this sort of
decentralized architecture where most of
情报掌握在客户中，所以第一个挑战是
the intelligence is sitting in the
clients so the first challenge is that
假设工作站在您创建的文件中知道一个可能是/ aa new的文件
suppose workstation one creates a file
in you know maybe a file say /a a new
文件/ a，最初它只是在其本地缓存中创建此文件，以便您知道
file /a and initially it just creates
this in its local cache so that you know
首先，它可能需要从中获取slash目录的当前内容。
first it may need to fetch the current
contents of the slash directory from
花瓣标称值，但是当它创建文件时，只需修改其缓存副本并
petal nom but then when it creates a
file just modifies its cached copy and
不会立即将其发送回兜售，这是一个直接的问题
doesn't immediately send it back to
peddle then there's an immediate problem
这里假设工作站2上的用户尝试获取目录的目录
here suppose the user on workstation 2
tries to get a directory listing of the
目录斜杠，我们非常希望能够使该用户看到新的
directory slash right we'd really like
to be able to this user see the newly
创建文件的权利，这就是用户的期望，用户将非常
created file right and that's what users
are gonna expect and users will be very
如果您认识我旁边的人感到困惑，创建了一个文件并说哦
confused if you know person down the
hall from me created a file and said oh
你知道我把所有这些有趣的信息放在这个新文件中/ a为什么
you know I put all this interesting
information in this new file /a why
你不去读它，然后我试着去读它，它完全不存在，所以我们
don't you go read it and then I try to
read it and it's totally not there so we
如果大厅里的人说他们已经
absolutely want very strong consistency
if the person down the hall says they've
在文件系统中完成了某些操作，我应该能够看到它，如果我编辑了
done something in the file system I
should be able to see it and if I edit a
文件放在一个工作站上，然后在另一台计算机上编译它
file on one work station and then maybe
compile it on a computer on another
计算机，我希望编译器查看我对文件所做的修改
computer I want the compiler to see the
modifications I just made to my file
这意味着文件系统必须做一些事情以确保读者能够看到
which means that the file system has to
do something to ensure that readers see
甚至是最近的版权，所以我们一直在谈论这一点
even the most recent rights so we've
been talking about this as we've been
称其为强先验性和线性化能力
calling this you know strong strong
consistency and linearize ability before
这基本上是我们在缓存上下文中想要的，尽管像问题一样
and that's basically what we want in the
context of caches though like the issue
这与存储服务器无关，实际上与事实有关
here is not really about the storage
server necessarily it's about the fact
在这里有一个修改，现在需要在其他地方看到
that there was a modification here that
needs to be seen somewhere else and now
由于历史原因，通常称为缓存一致性
for historical reasons that's usually
called cache coherence that is the
缓存系统的属性，即使我有旧版本的东西
property of a caching system that even
if I have an old version of something
如果其他人在其缓存中对其进行了修改，则该缓存将被缓存
cached if someone else modifies it in
their cache then my cache will
自动反映其修改，因此我们需要此缓存
automatically reflect their
modifications so we want this cache
一致性属性您遇到的另一个问题是，您了解所有一切
coherence property another issue you
have is that the you know everything all
文件和目录是共享的，我们很容易遇到两种情况
the files and directories are shared we
could easily have a situation where two
不同的工作站同时修改同一目录，因此
different workstations are modifying the
same directory at the same time so
再次假设也许工作站上的用户想要创建一个文件
suppose again maybe the user one on
their workstation wants to create a file
/ a是根目录中新目录中斜杠的新文件
/a which is a new file in the directory
slash in the new in the root directory
并且同时用户两个想要创建一个称为斜杠B的新文件，因此在
and at the same time user two wants to
create a new file called slash B so at
在某种程度上，您知道他们正在创建不同的文件a和B，但是它们
some level you know they're creating
different files alright a and B but they
两者都需要修改根目录以向根目录添加新名称
both need to modify the root directory
to add a new name to the root directory
所以问题是，即使他们同时执行此操作，您也知道要归档
and so the question is even if they do
this simultaneously you know to file
创建不同名称的文件，但位于不同目录的同一目录中
creations of differently named files but
in the same directory from different
工作站将使系统能够整理出这些并发的修改
workstations will the system be able to
sort out these concurrent modifications
到同一目录，并得出一些合理的结果，当然
to the same directory and arrive at some
sensible result and of course the
我们想要的明智结果是，a和B最终都存在，我们不想
sensible result we want is that both a
and B end up existing we don't want to
最终遇到一些您知道的情况，其中只有一个最终存在
end up with some you know situation in
which only one of them ends up existing
因为第二个修改覆盖并取代了
because the second modification
overwrote and sort of superseded the
第一次修改
first modification
所以这又一次使用了许多不同的名称，但我们称其为de
and so this is again it goes by a lot of
different names but we'll call it a de
Missa T我们想要诸如创建文件之类的操作来引导文件充当
Missa T we want operations such as
create a file to lead a file to act as
如果它们只是瞬时的，瞬时的，并且永远不会
if they just are instantaneous
instantaneous and time and don't ever
因此永远不要干扰在相似时间发生的操作
therefore don't ever interfere with
operations that occur at similar times
被其他工作站很好地发生在某个时刻
by other workstations
well things to happen just at a point in
时间并且不会分散，即使它们是复杂的操作并且涉及
time and not be spread over even if
they're complex operations and involve
接触到很多状态，我们希望它们像瞬间发生一样出现
touching a lot of state we want them to
appear as if they occur instantaneously
最后一个问题是，假设您知道我的工作站已被修改
at a final problem we have is suppose
you know my workstation is modified a
很多东西，也许是它的修改或很多
lot of stuff and maybe it's
modifications are or many of its
由于此右后缓存，因此只能在本地缓存中进行修改
modifications are done only in the local
cache because of this right back caching
如果在修改本地缓存中的某些内容后我的was station崩溃了
if my were station crashes after having
modified some stuff in its local cache
可能会将部分但不是全部修改反映回存储中
and maybe reflected some but not all
those modifications back to storage
踩其他工作站仍在执行，他们仍然需要能够
pedal other workstations are still
executing and they still need to be able
可以理解文件系统，因此我在工作站崩溃时
to make sense of the file system so the
fact that my workstation crashed while I
最好不要破坏整个文件系统
was in the middle of something had
better not wreck the entire file system
对于其他人甚至其中的任何部分，这意味着我们需要的是崩溃
for everybody else or even any part of
it so that means what we need is crash
恢复单个服务器，我们将无法使我的工作站崩溃
recovery of individual servers we won't
be able to have my workstation crash
不会干扰使用同一共享的其他人的活动
without disturbing the activity of
anybody else using the same shared
系统，即使他们查看我文件中的目录，也应该看到
system even if they look at my directory
in my files they should see something
明智的做法也许不会包括我所做的最后一件事，但他们应该看到
sensible maybe it won't include the very
last things I did but they should see a
一致的文件系统，而不是rekt文件系统的数据结构，因此我们需要
consistent file system and not a rekt
file system data structure so we want
崩溃恢复
crash recovery
与以往一样，分布式系统变得更加复杂，因为我们可以
很容易出现只有其中一台服务器崩溃而其他服务器崩溃的情况
easily have a situation where only one
of the servers crashes but the others
正在为所有这些事情而运行，并针对所有这三个挑战
are running and again for all of these
things for all three of these challenges
他们真的受到挑战，我们在这次讨论中
they're really challenged we're in this
discussion their challenges about how
鸡蛋花的工作原理以及这些鸡蛋花的用法
frangipani works and how these
frangipani
工作站内部的软件可以正常工作，所以当我谈论崩溃时，
software inside the workstations work
and so when I talk about a crash I'm
谈论工作站的崩溃和素馨花，你知道踏板
talking about a crash of a workstation
and it's frangipani you know the pedal
虚拟磁盘有许多与之相关的类似问题，但没有
virtual disk has many similar questions
associated with it but there are not
今天的焦点实际上是一组完全独立的R'lyeh断层
really the focus today it has a
completely separate set of R'lyeh fault
内置在踏板中的公差机械，实际上很像链条
tolerance machinery built into pedal and
it's actually a lot like the chain
复制类型的系统，我们之前讨论过，所以我要谈谈
replication kind of systems we talked
about earlier ok so I'm going to talk
关于这些挑战，第一个挑战是缓存一致性
about each of these challenges in turn
the first challenge is cache coherence
而这里的游戏是要同时获得线性化能力和
and the game here is to get both the
benefits of both linearize ability that
当我阅读文件系统中的任何内容时，总能看到新鲜的东西
is when I read when I look at anything
in the filesystem I always see fresh
数据我总是看到最新的数据，因此我们既具有线性化能力，又具有
data I always see the very latest data
so we got both linearize ability and
缓存不是缓存，这是很好的缓存，因为我们可以以某种方式获得性能
caching not caching that's good caching
as we can get for performance so somehow
我们知道，我们需要获得这些以及这些方面的好处
we you know we need to get the benefits
of both of these and the kind of that
人们使用所谓的缓存一致性来实现缓存一致性
people implement cache coherence that is
using what are called cache coherence
协议，事实证明这些协议在很多方面都得到了广泛使用
protocols and it turns out these
protocols are used a lot in many
不同情况不仅是分布式文件系统，还包括
different situations not just
distributed file systems but also things
就像多核中的高速缓存一样，多核处理器中的每核高速缓存
like the caches in multi-core the per
core caches in multi core processors
也使用缓存一致性协议，这些协议将与协议没有什么不同
also use cache coherence protocols which
are going to be not unlike the protocols
我要描述素馨花
I'm going to describe for frangipani all
right
因此事实证明，素馨花x的缓存一致性是由其使用锁驱动的
so it turns out that frangipani x' cache
coherence is driven by its use of locks
稍后我们会看到实际上是原子性和
and we'll see locks come up later in
both actually for both atomicity and
崩溃恢复，但是我现在要谈论的锁的特殊用法是
crash recovery but the particular use of
locks I'm going to talk about for now is
使用块来驱动缓存一致性，以帮助工作站确保
a use of blocks to drive cache coherence
to help workstations ensure that even
尽管他们在缓存数据，但他们也在缓存最新数据，以及
though they're caching data they're
caching the latest data so as well as
素馨花服务器，工作站和踏板服务器还有第三种
the frangipani servers and workstations
and pedal servers there's a third kind
在素馨花系统中的服务器上，有锁服务器，所以我们
of server in the frangipani system
there's lock servers and so we're I'm
只是假装有一个锁服务器，尽管您可以分片
just gonna pretend there's one lock
server although you could shard the
锁定多个服务器，所以这是一个锁定服务器，它是一个单独的
locks over multiple servers so here's a
lock server it's a separate you know
从逻辑上讲至少是一台单独的计算机，尽管我认为他们可以运行它们
it's logically at least a separate
computer although I think they ran them
在与踏板服务器相同的硬件上，但基本上只有一个
on the same hardware as the pedal
servers but it basically just has a
命名锁表和锁已命名，我们将认为它们以
table of named locks and locks are named
we'll consider them to be named after a
以文件名命名，尽管实际上它们是以I编号命名的，所以我们
named as after file names although in
fact they're named after I numbers so we
每个文件都有一个锁，每个锁都有可能
have for every file we have a lock
potentially and each lock is possibly
在此讨论中归某个所有者所有，我只是假设我要描述
owned by some owner for this discussion
I'm just gonna assume I'm gonna describe
好像锁是排他锁，尽管事实上鸡蛋花还有更多
it as if the locks were exclusive locks
although in fact frangipani has a more
复杂的锁方案，允许一个作者或多个读者
complicated scheme for locks that allow
either one writer or multiple readers so
例如，也许文件X最近已被工作站1使用，并且
for example maybe file X has recently
been used by workstation 1 and
工作站1上有一个锁，也许工作站2最近使用了文件Y
workstation 1 has a lock on it and maybe
file Y is recently used by workstation 2
并且工作站2上有一个锁，锁服务器将记住或
and workstation 2 has a lock on it and
the lock server will remember off or
每个有锁的文件，如果有人也许没人
each file
who has the lock if anyone maybe nobody
在该文件上执行，然后在每个工作站上执行
does on that file and then in each
workstation
每个工作站都跟踪其持有的锁，并将其紧密地绑在一起
each workstation keeps track of which
locks it holds and this is tightly tied
对此，我也在跟踪缓存数据
to it
I'm keeping track of cache data as well
因此在每个工作站素馨花模块中，还有一个锁表和一个
so in each workstations frangipani
module there's also a lock table and
记录更多文件以锁定哪种文件，并记录更多会话，以及
record what file the more session to
lock for what kind of lock it has and
该文件的缓存内容的内容，因此可能是一大堆
the contents the cached contents of that
file so that might be a whole bunch of
数据块或目录内容，例如，有很多内容
data blocks or maybe directory contents
for example so there's a lot of content
在这里，Linda鸡蛋花服务器决定了哦，需要阅读，需要使用
here so Linda frangipani server decides
oh it needs to read it needs to use the
目录斜杠或查看文件a或查看它首先被询问的索引节点
directory slash or look at the file a or
look at an inode it first gets asked the
锁定服务器以锁定将要使用的任何内容，然后要求花瓣
lock server for a lock on whatever it's
about to use and then it asks petal to
获取该文件或目录或其所需要的数据
get the data for whatever that file or
directory or whatever it is and it needs
阅读，然后工作站会记住哦，你知道我有副本
to read and then the workstation
remembers oh ho you know I have a copy
的文件X的内容与文件X的内容缓存的内容有关
of file X its content is whatever the
content of file X is cached and it turns
工作站可以在至少两种不同的模式下锁定
out that workstations can have a lock in
at least two different modes what the
工作站可以主动读取或写入该文件或目录
workstation can be actively reading or
writing whatever that file or directory
现在处于文件创建操作或删除操作的中间，或者
is right now that it's in the middle of
a file creation operation or deletion or
重命名之类的东西，在这种情况下，我会说锁是由
rename or something so in that case I'll
say that the lock is held by the
工作站并且很忙，也可能是工作站完成了一些操作之后
workstation and is busy it could also be
after a workstation has done some
创建文件或读取文件之类的操作
operation like create a file or maybe
read a file
您知道然后在系统调用完成后立即释放锁
you know then release the lock as soon
as it's done with that system call
任何系统调用，例如重命名，读取或写入或在系统创建后立即创建
whatever system call like rename or read
or write or create as soon as the system
工作站上的呼叫将至少在内部放弃锁，不是
calls over the workstation will give up
the lock at least internally it's not
主动使用该文件，但它将一直到锁定服务器为止
actively using that file anymore but
it'll as far as the lock server is
有关工作站将持有锁，但工作站会对此进行说明
concerned the workstation will hold the
lock but the workstation notes for it
它自己的用途是不再积极使用该锁，也称
its own use that it's not actively using
that lock anymore as well call that the
锁仍然是我所拥有的工作站，但工作站却没有
lock is still held by the workstation
I'm just but the work station isn't
真正地使用它，那一会儿很重要，所以我认为这两个
really using it and that'll be important
in a moment okay so I think these two
如果我们假设这是工作站之一，则设置一致
are set up consistently if we assume
this is workstation one the lock server
知道存在x和y的哦锁，并且它们都被工作站一持有
knows Oh locks for x and y exists and
they're both held by workstation one
工作站一在其表中具有等效信息，它知道
workstation one has equivalent
information in its table it knows it's
持有这两个街区，而且它具有记住内容的功能
holding these two blocks and furthermore
it has the it's remembering the content
被缓存为两个锁覆盖的目录的文件管理器
is cached for the filers of directories
that the two locks cover there's a
鸡蛋花中遵循的一些规则导致其使用
number of rules here that in that
frangipani follows that caused it to use
以提供高速缓存一致性的方式进行锁定，然后确保没人
locks in a way that provide cache
coherence then sure nobody's ever
意味着使用缓存中的过时数据，所以这些基本上是规则
meaning using stale data from their
cache so so these are basically rules
与锁一起使用并缓存数据，所以一个真正的
that are using conjunction with the
locks and cache data so one the really
这里最重要的是，不允许工作站将数据缓存到
overriding invariant here is that no
workstation is allowed to cache data to
保存所有缓存的数据，除非它还保存与该数据关联的锁
hold any cached data unless it also
holds the lock associated with that data
因此，基本上，没有锁就没有缓存数据，而没有锁可以保护
so basically it's no cache data without
a lock without the lock that protects
该数据及其在使用前的含义是工作站
that data and operationally what this
means is a workstation before it uses
数据时，它首先从锁定服务器获取对数据的锁定，然后
data it first acquires the lock on the
data from the lock server and after the
工作站只有锁才可以从花瓣中读取数据
workstation has the lock only then does
the workstation read the data from petal
并将其放入缓存中，这样顺序就可以获取锁
and put it and put it in its cache so so
the sequence is you can acquire a lock
然后从花瓣中读取
and then read from petal
我会告诉您，当然您知道您没有传递数据
I'll tell you at the lock of course you
know you weren't passing the data you
想捕获您首先必须获得锁定的数据，并且仅严格
want to catch the data you first got to
get the lock and only strictly
然后从花瓣上读取，如果您曾经释放过锁，则规则是
afterwards read from petal and if you
ever release a lock then the rule is
在释放锁之前，如果修改了锁，则首先必须编写
that before releasing a lock you first
have to write if you modified the lock
释放锁之前，缓存中的数据必须写回数据
data in your cache before you release
the lock you have to write the data back
修改数据回到花瓣，然后只有当花瓣是的时候，我得到了数据
to modify data back to petal and then
only when petals as yes I got the data
只有这样，您才必须释放该锁，该锁将锁返回给
only then you'll have to release the
lock that is gives a lock back to the
锁定服务器，因此序列始终是第一个，您写入日期为花瓣的缓存
lock server so the sequence is always
first you write the cache dated a petal
存储系统，然后释放锁
storage system and then release the lock
并删除条目，然后将条目删除，猫和
and erase the entry whoops
erase the entry and the cat and the
从您的工作站缓存表中缓存数据，这是什么
cache data from your from that
workstations lock table what this
导致锁定服务器之间和工作站之间的协议
results in the the protocol between the
lock server and between the workstations
锁服务器包含四种不同类型的消息，这是
and the lock server consists of four
different kinds of messages this is the
相干协议，这些只是网络，您可以将它们视为
coherence protocol these are just
network you can think of them as
本质上是一种单向网络消息，其中有一个请求消息
essentially sort of one-way Network
messages there's a request message from
从工作站到锁服务器的请求消息说，哦，嘿锁服务器
from workstations to the lock server
request message says oh hey lock server
当锁服务器愿意为您提供锁时，我想获得此锁
I'd like to get this lock when the lock
server is willing to give you the lock
当然，如果锁服务器不能立即放弃
and of course if somebody else holds if
the lock server can't immediately give
您的锁，但是如果锁释放后，锁服务器将
you the lock but if when the lock
becomes free the lock server will
响应我们有一条授权消息，然后将锁定服务器返回到工作站
respond we have a grant message then the
lock server back to the workstation in
如果您请求锁服务器的锁，则可以很好地响应先前的请求
response to an earlier request well if
you request a lock for the lock server
现在其他人必须先将锁交给其他人
and someone else holds the lock right
now that other workstation has to first
放弃锁，我们不能让两个人拥有同一把锁，那怎么办
give up the lock we can't have two
people owning the same lock so how are
我们要使锁工作得很好，我在这里说的是
we going to get that works
the lock well what I said here is that
您何时知道锁站何时实际使用锁，并且
when a lock station is you know when
it's actually using the lock and
积极阅读或写有锁的东西，并标记为忙，但
actively reading or writing something it
has the lock and it's marked it busy but
工作站在使用完毕后通常不会放弃锁
the workstations don't give up their
locks ordinarily when they're done using
他们，所以如果我创建文件然后创建系统调用完成，我仍然
them so if I if I create a file and then
create system call finishes I'll still
将该文件锁定为新文件，并拥有该文件的锁
have that file that new file locked and
also own the lock for that my
工作站仍将对该文件保持锁定状态
workstation will still all in the lock
for that file it'll just be in state
空闲而不是忙，但就锁定服务器而言
idle instead of busy but as far as the
lock server is concerned
好吧，我的工作站仍然有锁，原因是
well my workstation still has the lock
and the reason for this the reason to be
关于将锁交还给锁服务器的懒惰是，如果我创建一个文件
lazy about handing locks back to the
lock server is that if I create a file
我的工作站上叫Y，几乎可以肯定
called Y on my workstation
I'm almost certainly going to be about
将Y用于其他目的，例如向其中写入一些数据或从中读取数据，或者
to use Y for other purposes like maybe
write some data to it or read from it or
因此，对于工作站而言，
something so it's extremely advantageous
for the workstation to sort of
为工作站中所有最近使用的文件积累锁，而不是
accumulate locks for all of the recently
used files in the workstation and not
除非确实需要，否则将它们还给他人。
give them back unless it really has to
and so in the ordinary in the common
在这种情况下，我在主目录中使用了一堆文件，而在其他任何人上都没有其他人
case in which I use a bunch of files in
my home directory and nobody else on any
其他工作站曾经看着他们我的工作站最终积累了数十个
other workstation ever looks at them my
workstation ends up accumulating dozens
或成百上千个处于空闲状态的文件锁，但是如果其他人确实找到了
or hundreds of locks in idle state for
my files but if somebody else does look
在我的一个文件中，他们需要首先获得锁，而我必须放弃
at one of my files they need to first
get the lock and I have to give up the
锁定，因此有效的方式是，如果锁定服务器收到锁定请求
lock so the way that works is that if
the lock server receives a lock request
并且它在锁服务器表AHA中看到您知道锁当前由所有者拥有
and it sees in the lock server table AHA
you know that lock is currently owned by
工作站1，锁定服务器将向任何人发送撤销消息
workstation 1 the lock server will send
a revoke message to whoever the
当前拥有该锁的工作站，说您知道其他人
workstation that currently owns that
lock saying look you know somebody else
希望它在工作站收到撤销请求时放弃锁，如果
wants it please give up the lock when a
workstation receives a revoke request if
锁是空闲的，然后如果缓存数据脏了，工作站将首先
the lock is idle then if the cache data
is dirty the workstation will first
将修改了缓存中的数据的猫脏数据写回兜售
write the cat dirty data that modified
data from his cache back to peddle
因为该规则说这样的规则：为了不加锁就永远不缓存数据
because the rule says the rule that in
order to never cache data without a lock
说我们没错，修改的日期可以追溯到发布之前的价格，所以如果
says we got our right the modify dated
back to peddle before releasing so if
如果将锁修改为peddle，则空闲的锁将首先写回数据
the locks idle would first write back
the data if it's modified back to peddle
然后将消息发送回锁
and
then send a message back to the lock
服务器说没关系，我们放弃了此锁定，因此撤销响应发送到了
server saying it's okay we give up this
lock so the response to revoke send to a
工作站是最差的工作站，如果最坏的工作站当然会释放它
workstation is the worst station sends
it released of course if the worst
工作站在处于活动状态时正在使用锁时会被撤销
station gets a revoke while it's
actively using a lock while it's in the
删除或重命名的中间或影响锁定文件的内容
middle of a delete or rename or
something that affects the locked file
最糟糕的站点在使用完成之前不会给我们锁定
the worst station will not give us a
lock until it's it's done using and
直到完成该文件系统操作为止，无论它是什么系统调用
until it's finished that file system
operation whatever system call it was
使用该文件，然后在最差的站点处于锁定状态时锁定
that was using this file and then the
lock in the worst stations lock state
将过渡到空闲状态，然后您就可以注意撤销
will transition to idle and then you'll
be able to pay attention to the revoke
请求并写到小贩后，如果需要的话，释放锁好
request and after writing to peddle if
need be released the lock alright so
这是边缘协议，这是一个相干协议
this is the is the coherence protocol
that fringe that well this is a
我提到过的素馨花使用的一致性协议的简化
simplification of the coherence protocol
that frangipani uses as I mentioned
在这一切缺失之前，锁可以是
before what's missing from all this is
the fact that locks can be either
专为作家使用，或为只读访问而共享，就像花瓣是
exclusive for writers or shared for
read-only access and just like petal is
块服务器并且对文件系统一无所知
a block server and doesn't understand
anything about file systems the lock
服务器也是这些ID，这些ID确实是锁标识符，而锁是
server also these IDs these are really
lock identifiers and the locks are
对文件，目录或文件系统一无所知
doesn't know anything about files or
directories or file system it just has
这些只是带有不透明ID的表格，谁拥有您知道
these it's just has this table with
opaque IDs and who owns you know that
名字锁，谁拥有这些锁，是素馨花，你知道啊
name locks and who owns those locks and
it's frangipani that knows ah you know
我关联的锁是他给的文件，具有这样的标识符和
the lock that I associate was he given a
file has such and such an identifier and
碰巧，prin Japan使用unix样式的I编号或与
as it happens prin Japan uses unix-style
I numbers or the numbers associated with
文件而不是锁的名称，以便使此一致性协议具体化
files instead of names for locks so just
to make this coherence protocol concrete
并再次说明花瓣操作之间的关系
and to illustrate again the relationship
between petal operations
和锁定服务器操作让我可以简单地了解一下
and lock server operations let me just
run through what happens if one
工作站修改一些文件系统数据，然后在另一个工作站中
workstation modifies some file system
data and then in another workstation
意味着要看一下，所以我们有两个工作站，锁服务器，这样
means to look at it so we have two
workstations the lock server so the way
如果工作站要自工作站读取该协议，则会播放该协议
the protocol plays out if workstation
one wants to read since a workstation
一个人想要读取然后修改文件e，以便它甚至可以读取任何内容之前
one wants to read and then modify files
e so before it can even read anything
大约要从小贩处获得Z，它必须首先获取Z的锁，以便它发送
about Z from peddle it must first
acquire the lock for Z so it sends an
获取对锁定服务器的请求，也许没有人持有一个或多个锁定服务器
acquire request to the lock server maybe
nobody holds the lock or lock servers
从来没有听说过它，所以锁是Z的新输入
never heard anything about it
so the locks are makes a new entry for Z
它稳定返回我们的答复，说是
and it stable returns our reply saying
yes
您拥有锁C的授予，此时工作站表示它具有
you own the grant for lock C and at this
point the workstation says it has the
锁定文件Z无权从花瓣读取有关它的信息，因此在
lock on file Z isn't entitled to read
information about it from petal so at
这一点，我们将从花瓣上读取Z
this point we're gonna read Z from petal
确实，工作站可以稍后在本地对其缓存中进行修改
and indeed workstation one can modify it
locally in their cache at some later
也许人类和坐在工作站前的两个人想
point maybe the human being and sitting
in front of workstation two wants to
也可以在工作站2没有锁的情况下读取文件Z
also to read file Z while the
workstation two doesn't have the lock
对于文件ISA，它要做的第一件事就是发送一条消息
for files the ISA the very first thing
it needs to do is send a message the
锁服务器说哦，是的，我想获取文件Z的锁，锁服务器
lock server saying oh yeah I'd like to
get the lock for file Z the lock server
知道它不能回答是，因为其他人拥有锁
knows it can't reply yes yet because
somebody else has the lock namely
我的锁定服务器发送响应的工作站之一吊销
一个工作站，一个工作站，直到它放弃之前，都不放弃锁
the workstation one workstation one not
allowed to give up the lock until it
将所有修改后的数据写回踏板，现在就可以写模型了
writes any modified data back to the
pedal so it's now gonna write the model
任何修改过的内容，文件的实际内容始终
anything modified content the actual
contents of the file with always
修改回踏板才允许工作站2发送
释放回锁定服务器，锁定服务器必须在其中保存了一条记录
release back to the lock server the lock
server with must have kept a record in
一张桌子说好，你知道有人在等锁Z
some table saying well you know there's
somebody waiting for lock Z as soon as
当前持有人的版本，我们需要回复，因此，此收据
its current holder releases that we need
to reply and so this receipt of this
释放将导致锁服务器更新其表并最终发送
release will cause the lock server to
update its tables and finally send the
授予第二站或第二站，此时我们的第二站终于可以
grant back to or station two and at this
point now our station two can finally
甚至可以读取文件，这就是缓存一致性协议如何发挥作用的原因
read files even pedal this is how the
cache coherence protocol plays out to
确保进行读取的每个人直到谁
ensure that everybody who does a read
doesn't read the data until whoever the
直到有人将数据私下修改过
previous until anybody who might have
had the data modified privately in their
缓存首先将数据写回到踏板上，这样锁定机器
cache first writes the data back to
pedal all right so the locking machinery
部队阅读以查看最新的权利，所以这是怎么回事
forces reads to see the latest right so
what's going on there's a number of the
在此类缓存一致性协议中可能进行的优化
optimizations that are possible in these
kind of cache coherence protocols
我的意思是我实际上已经描述了这种空闲状态，
I mean I've actually already described
one this idle state the fact that
工作站持有他们现在不使用的锁，而不是
workstations hold onto locks that
they're not using right now instead of
立即发布它们，这已经是最简单的优化
immediately releasing them that's
already an optimization to the simplest
您可以想到的协议，另一个主要的优化是鸡蛋花
protocol you can think of and the other
main optimization is that the frangipani
它具有共享，共享读锁和共享的概念。
has is that it has a notion of shared
versus shared read locks versus
排他性写锁，因此需要很多工作站
exclusive write locks so have lots and
lots of workstations need to be
相同的文件，但是没有人在写，他们都可以拥有读锁定
the same file but nobody's writing it
they can all have a lock a read lock on
该文件，如果有人确实来尝试写这个文件
that file and if somebody does come
along and try to write this file that's
被广泛缓存的他们首先需要先撤销每个人的读取锁，以便
widely cached they first need to first
revoke everybody's read lock so that
每个人都放弃其缓存的副本，然后才是权利或被允许写
everybody gives up their cached copy and
only then is a right or allowed to write
该文件，但现在还可以，因为没有人拥有缓存副本，因此
the file but it's okay now because
nobody has a cache copy anymore so
没有人会在正确写入数据的同时读取过时的数据，因此这是一个
nobody could be reading stale data while
it's being written all right so that's a
缓存一致性故事由我们接下来的锁定协议驱动
cache coherence story driven by driven
by the locking protocol next up in our
是的列表，这是一个好问题，实际上，这里存在风险
list of yes yes that's a good question
in fact there's a risk here in the
我描述的方案是，如果我在工作站上修改了文件而没有其他人
scheme I described that if I modify a
file on my workstation and nobody else
读给别人读，只有修改的文件的唯一副本
reads it for nobody else reads it that
the only copy of the modified file maybe
我的RAM中的缓存中有一些宝贵的信息
have some precious information in it is
on in in the cache in RAM on my
工作站和我的作品，然后它们崩溃了，你知道我们还没有完成
workstation and my works they were to
crash then and you know we hadn't done
任何特殊的东西，它将与数据的唯一副本崩溃
anything special then it would have
crashed with the only copy of the data
并且数据将丢失，因此为了防止这种情况发生，无论如何
and the data would be lost so in order
to forestall this no matter what all
这些工作站会写回其缓存中的所有内容以及任何已修改的内容
these workstations write back anything
that's in their cache any modified stuff
每30秒在其缓存中保存一次，这样，如果我的工作站意外崩溃
in their cache every 30 seconds so that
if my workstation crash is unexpectedly
我可能会失去最后30秒的工作时间，但实际上没有更多的模仿了
I may lose the last 30 seconds at work
but no more there's actually just mimics
普通Linux或UNIX的工作方式
the way ordinary Linux or UNIX works
确实，所有这一切的故事都是关于分布式环境的
indeed all of this a lot of the story is
about in the context of a distributed
文件系统试图模仿普通unix风格的属性
file system trying to mimic the
properties that ordinary unix-style
工作站使用户不会对素馨花感到惊讶，只是
workstations have so that users won't be
surprised by frangipani it just sort of
与他们已经使用的方式大致相同
works much the same way that they're
already used
好的，所以我们的下一个挑战是如何实现原子性
all right so our next challenge is how
do you atomicity that is how to make it
所以即使我做一个复杂的操作，例如创建一个文件
so even though when I do a complex
operation like creating a file which
毕竟涉及标记一个新的我知道分配分配初始化
after all involves marking a new I
knowed as allocated initializing the
索引节点我知道一些描述每个文件的数据
inode the I knows a little piece of data
that describes each file maybe
为文件分配空间，在我的新目录中添加新名称
allocating space for the file adding a
new name in the directory for my new
文件有很多步骤，很多事情我们都不需要更新
file there's many steps so many things
that have to be updated we don't want
任何人看到任何中间步骤，我们都希望您认识的其他人
anybody to see any of the intermediate
steps we want people you know other
工作站看到文件不存在或完全存在但不存在
workstations to either see the file not
exist or completely exist but not
一个原子之间的东西
something in between one atomic
多步操作好吧，以便于执行此操作以使
multi-step operations alright so in
order to implement this in order to make
文件创建或重命名或删除原子等多步骤操作
multi-step operations like file create
or rename or delete atomic as far as
其他工作站都关注素馨花有一个工具的概念
other workstations are concerned
frangipani has a implement the notion of
作为一种完整的数据库样式事务处理系统的事务
transactions that is as a complete sort
of database style transaction system
再次由锁驱动
inside it again driven by the locks
此外，这实际上是分布式交易系统
furthermore it it's it's this is
actually distributed transaction system
我们将在以后看到更多有关分布式事务处理系统的信息。
and we'll see more we'll hear more about
distributed transaction systems later in
当然有一个非常普遍的要求
the course
there are like a very common requirement
和分布式系统这里的基本故事是鸡蛋花
and distributed systems the basic story
here is that frangipani makes it so that
其他工作站在完成以下操作之前看不到我的修改：
other workstations can't see my
modifications until completely done by
首先获取我要访问的所有数据的所有锁的操作
an operation by first acquiring all the
locks on all the data that I'm going to
在操作过程中需要读或写，并且不释放任何一个
need to read or write during my
operation and not releasing any of those
锁定，直到完成完整的操作为止，当然
locks until it's finished with the
complete operation and of course
遵循一致性规则，将所有修改后的数据写回到花瓣
following the coherence rule written all
of the modified data back to petal
所以在我进行重命名之类的操作之前，例如从一个文件中移动文件
so before I do an operation like
renaming like moving a file from one
目录到另一个毕竟修改了两个目录，我不
directory to another which after all
modifies both directories and I don't
希望任何人都能看到该文件位于目录中或目录中
want anybody to see the file being in
either directory or something in the
为了做这个手术中间要先做法国的一分钱
middle of the operation in order to do
in order to do this French penny first
获取操作需要所有的锁，然后像所有一样做所有事情
acquires require all the locks for the
operation then do everything like all
素馨花的更新，所以我写到踏板，然后释放和
the updates right the frangipani so I
write to pedal and then release and of
当然，这是个简单的按钮，您会知道，因为我们已经拥有锁定服务器
course this is easy button and you know
since we already had the locking server
无论如何，为了驱动缓存一致性协议，我们仅由您购买
anyway in order to drive the cache
coherence protocol we buy just by you
知道确保在整个操作过程中都持有所有锁
know making sure we hold all the locks
for the entire duration of an operation
我们几乎免费获得了这些不可分割的原子交易，因此
we get these indivisible atomic
transactions almost for free so an
有趣的事情，基本上这就是所有要说的
interesting thing to know and that's
basically all there is to say about
使操作原子化并转移Pandu拥有所有锁
making operations atomic and transit
Pandu's hold all the locks an
关于锁的使用有趣的是，使用便士的趋势
interesting thing about this use of
locks is that trends of pennies using
锁定的目的-缓存一致性的几乎相反的目的素馨花使用
locks for - almost opposite purposes for
cache coherence frangipani uses the
锁定以确保任何想要的人都能立即看到写入内容
locks to make sure that writes are
visible immediately to anybody who wants
读取它们，因此这基本上就是使用锁来确保
to read them so this is all about using
locks essentially to kind of make sure
人们可以看到使用此块写的内容就是确保人们
people can see writes this use the
blocks is all about making sure people
在完成操作之前，看不到写入内容，因为我持有所有
don't see the writes until I'm finished
with an operation because I hold all the
锁定，直到所有权利都已完成，以便它们在播放
locks until all the rights have been
done so they're sort of playing an
通过重用他们本来必须拥有的锁在这里有趣的把戏
interesting trick here by reusing the
locks they would have had to have anyway
事务以提高缓存一致性
for transactions in order to drive cache
coherence
好的，所以下一个有趣的事情是崩溃恢复，我们需要应对
all right so the next interesting thing
is crash recovery we need to cope with
最有趣的可能性是工作站
the possibility the most interesting
possibility is that a workstation
持有锁时以及在某种复杂集合中间时崩溃
crashes while holding locks and while in
the middle of some sort of complex set
的更新是重新造林获得了一堆锁，它正在编写
of updates that is a reforestation
acquired a bunch of locks it's writing a
可能用于创建或删除文件的全部数据
whole lot of data to maybe create or
delete files or something has possibly
将一些修改写回踏板，因为也许很快
written some of those modifications back
to pedal because maybe it was gonna soon
释放锁或已被锁服务器要求释放锁，因此它是
release locks or had been asked by the
lock server to release locks so it's
也许因为其复杂的操作而获得了一些权利，但没有
maybe done some of the rights back to
pedal for its complex operations but not
所有这些，然后在放弃锁之前崩溃，这就是
all of them and then crashes before
giving up the locks so that's the
崩溃恢复的有趣情况，所以有很多事情
interesting situation for crash recovery
so there's a number of things that that
对于工作站崩溃崩溃不是很好，我们希望有一件事
don't work very well for workstation
crashes crashing we hope one thing that
不能很好地工作只是观察工作站崩溃和
doesn't work very well is to just
observe the workstations crashed and
只需释放其所有锁，因为如果完成了诸如创建一个
just release all its locks because then
if it's done something like created a
新文件并将其写入文件目录条目，其名称将返回到踏板
new file and it's written the files
directory entry its name back to pedal
但尚未编写描述
but it hasn't yet written the
initialized inode that describes the
文件inode可能仍然充满垃圾或先前的文件
file the inode may still be filled with
garbage or the previous file some
花瓣中的先前文件信息，但我们已经编写了目录
previous files information in petal and
yet we've already written the directory
条目，所以只释放已崩溃的文件服务器是不可行的
entry so it's not okay to just release a
crashed file servers release of crash
站锁定了另一件不好的事情是不释放崩溃
were stations locks another thing that's
not okay is to not release the crashed
工作站锁，您知道那是正确的，因为您知道是否
workstations locks you know that would
be correct because you know if it
在写出一些修改时崩溃了，事实是
crashed while in the middle of writing
out some of this modifications the fact
它没有全部写出就意味着无法释放其锁
that it hadn't written out all of them
means a can't of release its locks
所以简单地不释放它的锁是正确的，因为它会隐藏这个
so simply not releasing its locks is
correct because it would hide the this
来自任何读者的部分更新，因此不会有人看到
partial update from any readers and so
nobody would ever be confused by seeing
另一方面，您知道花瓣中的部分更新的数据结构
partially updated data structures in
petal on the other hand you know then
您需要使用这些文件的任何人都将永远等待锁
anybody you needed to use those files
would have to wait forever for the locks
如果我们只是不放弃他们，那么我们绝对必须放弃锁
if we simply didn't give them up so we
absolutely have to give up the locks in
为了使其他工作站可以使用该系统，可以使用这些相同的文件，并且
order that other workstations can use
the system can use those same files and
目录，但我们必须对工作站进行一些处理
directories but we have to do something
about the fact that the workstation
可能已经获得了部分权利，但不是全部，因此素馨花
might have done some of the rights but
not all for its operations so frangipani
与几乎其他所有需要实施崩溃可恢复的系统一样
has like almost every other system that
needs to implement crashed recoverable
交易用户立即登录
transactions users right ahead logging
这是我们至少在最近一次演讲中看到的一个例子
this is something we've seen at least
one instance of the last lecture with
与aurora一起使用时，我也使用了提前记录功能，因此，如果
with aurora i was also using right ahead
logging so the idea is that if a
工作站需要执行涉及触摸的复杂操作
workstation needs to do a complex
operation that involves touching
很好地更新文件系统中花瓣中的许多数据
updating many pieces of data in petal in
the file system the workstation well
首先，在授予花瓣任何权利之前，将la log条目附加到他的日志中
first before it makes any rights to
petal append a la log entry to his log
在花瓣中描述了它将要完成的全部操作，并且仅
in petal describing the full set of
operations it's about to do and only
当描述整个操作的日志条目安全地放在花瓣中时
when that log entry describing the full
set of operations is safely in petal
现在只有其他人可以看到它，工作站才能开始发送
where now anybody else can see it only
then will the workstation start to send
花瓣手术的权利我是，所以我们如果它能站
the rights for the operation out to
petal I'm so we if it were station could
甚至揭露了一项手术所必须拥有的花瓣权利
ever reveal even the one of its rights
for an operation the petal it must have
已经放置了描述整个操作的日志条目，所有更新必须
already put the log entry describing the
whole operation all of the updates must
已经存在于花瓣中，所以这是非常标准的，这只是对
already exist in petal so this is very
standard this is just a description of
马上进行伐木，但是有几个奇怪的方面
right ahead logging
but there's a couple of odd aspects of
素馨花如何实现即时伐木
how frangipani implements right ahead
logging
第一个是，在大多数交易系统中，只有一个日志
the first one is that in most
transaction systems there's just one log
您知道系统中的所有交易都坐在那里
and all the transactions in the system
you know they're all sitting there in
一本登录一个地方，所以发生了车祸，还有歌剧，不止一个
one log in one place so there's a crash
and there's opera there's more than one
影响同一数据的操作，我们拥有所有这些操作
operation that affects the same piece of
data we have all of those operations for
单个日志序列中的那部分数据和其他所有内容
that piece of data and everything else
right there in the single log sequence
因此，例如，我们知道哪个是给定片段的最新更新
and so we know for example which is the
most recent update to a given piece of
大卫，但素馨花不这样做，因为她的工作站日志是一个
David but frangipani doesn't do that
this it has her work station logs as one
每个工作站的日志，还有单独的日志，另一个非常有趣
log per work station and there's
separate logs the other very interesting
素馨花缓解日志系统的问题是LA工作站会记录日志
thing about frangipane ease logging
system is that the LA workstation logs
在几乎每个使用该系统的系统中，它们都存储在花瓣中，而不是存储在本地磁盘中
are stored in petal and not on local
disk in almost every system that uses
记录日志与正在运行的任何计算机紧密相关
logging the log is tightly associated
with whatever computer is running the
几乎总是保存在本地磁盘上的事务
transactions that it's almost always
kept on a local disk but for extremely
鸡蛋花工作站的充分理由
good reasons
frangipani workstations
将他们的日志存储在共享存储区中的花瓣中，每个工作站都有自己的存储区
store their logs in petal in the shared
storage each workstation had its own
一种半私人日志，但是它存储在花瓣存储中，如果
sort of semi-private log but it's stored
in petal storage where if the
工作站崩溃，其他工作站可以获取其日志，因此
workstation crashes its log can be
gotten that by other workstations so the
日志在花瓣中，这就像工作站的单独日志
logs are in petal and this is this is
like separate logs for workstation
存储在公共共享存储中的其他地方，就像一个非常
stored somewhere else in public sort of
shared storage so like a very
有趣且不寻常的安排，所以我们有点需要大致了解
interesting and unusual arrangement all
right so we kind of need to know roughly
法律上有什么日志条目中有什么
what's in the law what's in a log entry
不幸的是，关于日志条目格式的论文不是很明确
and unfortunately the papers not super
explicit about the format of a log entry
但是我们可以想象，论文确实说每个工作站
but we can imagine that the well the
paper does say that each workstations
原木位于一个已知的位置，在花瓣和
log sits in a known place a known range
of block numbers in petal and
此外，每个工作站都在某种情况下使用其日志空间和花瓣
furthermore that each workstation uses
its log space and petal on a kind of in
从头到尾都是循环的日志条目
a circular way that it is all right log
entries along from the beginning and
到达最后时，工作站将返回并重用其日志空间
when it hits the end the workstation
will go back and reuse its log space
回到其日志区域的开头，这当然意味着
back at the beginning of its log area
and of course that means that were
工作站需要能够知道清理日志，以确保
stations need to be able to you know
clean their logs so that sort of ensure
在重复使用该空间之前不需要日志条目，我将讨论
that a log entry isn't needed before
that space is reused and I'll talk about
一点点，但每个日志都包含一系列日志条目，每个日志条目
that in a bit but each a log consists of
a sequence of log entries each log entry
有一个日志序列号，每个工作站只是一个递增的数字
has a log sequence number it's just an
increasing number each workstation
数字是日志条目1 2 3 4 5，其直接原因可能是
numbers it's log entries 1 2 3 4 5 and
the immediate reason for this may be the
本文提及的唯一原因是，法国人的方式
only reason for this that the paper
mentions is that the the way that French
如果工作站崩溃，便士只会检测到工作站日志的结尾
penny just detects the end of a work
stations log if the work station crashes
通过扫描其登录花瓣中的单词，直到看到增加
is by scanning for words in its log in
petal until it sees the increasing
序列停止增加，然后它知道具有最高的日志条目
sequence stop increasing and it knows
then that the log entry with the highest
日志序列号必须是最后一个条目，因为它需要
log sequence number must be the very
last entry as it needs to be able to
检测到日志的结尾，确定，所以我们有了这个日志序列号，然后我
detect the end of the log ok so we have
this log sequence number and then I
相信每个日志实际上都有一个数组
believe each log actually has an an
array
模型aughh条目的描述集具有
of descriptions of model aughh entry has
an array of the descriptions of the
修改涉及到的所有不同修改
modifications all the different
modifications that were involved in a
特定操作或某些文件系统系统调用的操作，因此每个
particular operation or an operation of
some a file system system call so each
数组中的条目将具有一个块号，它是
entry in the array is going to have a
block number it's a block number in
花瓣上有一个版本号，稍后我们将介绍
petal there's a version number which
we'll get to in a bit and then there's
要写入的数据，因此需要一堆描述
the data to be written and so there's a
bunch of these required to describe
可能涉及文件系统中多个数据的一种操作
operations that might touch more than
one piece of data in the file system one
需要注意的是，日志仅包含有关更改的信息
thing to notice is that the log only
contains information about changes to
目录，索引节点和分配位图中的元数据
metadata that is to directories and
inodes and allocation bitmaps in the
文件系统中，日志实际上并不包含写入到
file system the log doesn't actually
contain the data that is written to the
它不包含用户数据的文件内容，仅包含信息
contents of files it doesn't contain the
user's data it just contains information
足够的信息以使文件系统结构在
enough information to make the file
systems structures recoverable after a
崩溃，例如，如果我在要创建的目录中创建名为F的文件
crash so for example if I create a file
called F in a directory that's gonna
会产生一个新的日志条目，其中包含两个关于修改的小描述
result in a new log entry that has two
little descriptions of modifications in
它描述了如何初始化新文件inode和
it one a description of how to
initialize the new files inode and in
放置在新文件目录中的新名称的另一种描述
another description of a new name to be
placed in the new files directory
好吧，我没有提到的一件事，当然，日志实际上是一个序列
alright so one thing I didn't mention so
of course the log is really a sequence
这些日志条目中的
of these log entries
最初是为了能够尽快进行修改
initially in order to be able to do
modifications as fast as possible
最初，一个朋友日语工作站日志仅存储在
initially a friend Japanese workstations
log is only stored inside the
工作站拥有自己的内存，除非必须
workstations own memory and won't be
written back to peddle until it has to
就是这样，这样您就知道写任何东西，包括将日志条目兜售
be and that's so that you know writing
anything including log entries to peddle
您知道这需要很长时间，因此我们希望避免甚至回写日志条目
you know it takes a long time so we want
to avoid even writing log entries back
兜售以及将脏数据或修改后的块写回到兜售
to peddle as well as writing dirty data
or modified blocks back to peddle we'd
想要避免尽可能长地这样做，所以对于
like to avoid doing that as long as
possible so the real full story for what
当工作站从锁定服务器收到吊销消息并看到该消息时发生
happens when a workstation gets a revoke
message from the lock server seeing that
它必须放弃一定的锁定，依此类推
it has to give up a certain lock so on
现在，这是一样的，尽管运动型的
right now this is the same you know this
is though compared sporto's
如果工作站收到吊销消息，则协议吊销消息
protocols revoke message if the
workstation gets a revoke message the
它必须采取的一系列步骤是：首先，这是非常重要的事情，
series of steps it must take is first
it's great that's the right any parts of
它的日志仅在内存中，尚未写入兜售
its log that are only in memory and
haven't yet been written to peddle it's
必须确保日志已完成并且第一步是踩踏板，所以它写道
got to make sure as log is complete and
pedal as the first step so it writes
它很长，只有这样，它才写入由
it's long and only then does it write
any updated blocks that are covered by
被撤销的锁，所以写修改后的块
the lock that's being revoked so write
modified blocks
只是为了引起锁定，然后
just for that provoked to lock and then
发送发布消息以及此排序和严格的原因
send a release message and the reason
for this sequencing and for this strict
禁止的是，如果我们将这些修改写给小贩，您将知道它们
ban is that these modifications if we
write them to peddle you know their
修改数据结构，文件系统数据结构以及是否
modifications to the data structure the
file system data structure and if we
像往常一样要通过婴儿新闻盒中途崩溃
were to crash midway through baby news
box just as usual we want to make sure
那其他工作站别人有足够的信息
that some other workstation somebody
else there's enough information to be
能够完成作业站的修改集
able to complete the set of
modifications that the were station is
即使工作站崩溃了也可能没有完成操作
made even though the workstation has
crashed and maybe didn't finish doing
这些权利并首先写日志，这将使我们能够
these rights and writing the log first
it's gonna be what allows us to
完成这些日志记录是对这些内容的完整描述
accomplish it these these log records
are a complete description of what these
修改将是这样，首先我们要知道，虽然
modifications are going to be so first
we you know first we write though the
完成日志到花瓣，然后我们的工作站可以开始写它了
complete log to petal and then we
workstation can start writing its
修改过的块，您可能崩溃了，也许不是
modified blocks you know maybe it
crashes maybe doesn't hopefully not and
如果完成编写为修改后的块，则可以发送发布
if it finishes writing as modified
blocks then it could send the release
回到锁服务器，这样您就知道我的工作站是否修改了一堆
back to the lock server so you know if
my workstation has modified a bunch of
文件，然后其他工作站想要读取这些文件之一，这是
files and then some other workstation
wants to read one of those files this is
发生锁定的顺序，所以曾经向我要锁
the sequence that happens lock so ever
asked me for my locks right back my
工作站右后说日志然后右后
workstation right back said log then
right back
将脏的已修改的块写入peddle，然后释放，然后
writes the dirty modified blocks to
peddle and only then releases and then
另一个工作站可以获取锁并读取这些块，因此
the other workstation can acquire the
lock and read these blocks so that's
某种非崩溃，您知道是否不会发生崩溃，这就是
sort of the non crash you know if a
crash doesn't happen that is the
当然，只有当发生崩溃时，这才是有趣的
sequence of course it's only interesting
if a crash happens yes
[音乐]
[Music]
好的，对于您绝对正确的日志，它将写入整个日志，是的
okay so for the log you're absolutely
right it writes the entire log and yeah
因此，如果我们撤销特定文件，工作站将
so so if if we get a revoke for a
particular file the workstation will
写下整个日志，然后仅是因为它只是放弃了
write its entire log and then only it's
only because it's only giving up the
锁定Z，它只需要写回Z覆盖的数据，所以我有
lock for Z it it only needs to write
back data that's covered by Z so I have
将整个日志仅写入锁所覆盖的数据
to write the whole log just the data
that's covered by the lock that we
需要放弃，然后我们可以释放该锁，是的，你知道，也许
needed to give up and then we can
release that lock so yeah you know maybe
如果结果是这样的话，那么写整个日志可能会像你一样矫kill过正
this writing the whole log might be
overkill like you if it turned out you
知道所以这是一个优化，您可能会或可能不会在乎
know so here's an optimization that you
might or might not care about if the
锁的配置文件Z的最后修改是放弃这个，但是
last modification for profile Z for the
lock were giving up is this one but
日志中的后续条目没有修改该文件，那么我可以编写
subsequent entries in my log didn't
modify that file then I could just write
只是我在内存中的日志的这个前缀回到了花瓣，你知道要懒惰
just this prefix of my in-memory log
back to petal and you know be lazy about
写剩下的，也许有一天我会看到
writing the rest and that might see me
sometime
我可能必须写回日志，实际上尚不清楚，我可以为我们节省很多时间
I might have to write the log back it's
actually not clear I would save us a lot
时间我们无论如何都要写回日志，是的，我认为花瓣
of time we have to write the log back at
some point anyway and yeah I think petal
只是写整个事情好吧好吧，所以现在我们可以谈谈当
just writes the whole thing okay okay so
now we can talk about what happens when
保持锁定状态时工作站崩溃，这是您需要
a workstation crashes while holding
locks right it's you know needs to
修改一些东西重命名一个文件创建一个文件，不管它是什么
modify something rename a file create a
file whatever it's acquired all the
锁定它需要修改其自身缓存中的某些内容以反映这些
locks it needs it's modified some stuff
in its own cache to reflect these
操作可能将一些东西写回到花瓣上，然后使人坠毁
operations maybe written some stuff back
to petal and then crashed men possibly
在写作过程中，所以有很多地方可能会崩溃
midway through writing so there's a
number of points at which it could crash
对，因为这始终是序列，总是在之前
right because this is always the
sequence it always just always before
从缓存写回修改后的块
writing modified blocks from the cache
back
素馨花总是会首先写上它的记录踏板，这意味着
the frangipani will always have written
it's logged pedal first that means that
如果发生崩溃，则是在最糟糕的站点写信给我们时，登录回
if a crash happens it's either while the
worst station is writing us log back to
踏板，但在写入之前，任何修改过的文件或目录都将被阻止
pedal but before it's written any
modified file or directory' blocks back
否则在回写这些修改后的块时会崩溃，因此
or it crashes while it's writing these
modified block back but therefore
肯定是在将其写入整个日志之后，所以这是一个非常
definitely after it's written in its
entire log and so that's a very
您知道很重要，但也许崩溃是在完全完成之后发生的
important you know but or maybe the
crash happened after it's completely
完成了所有这些操作，所以您知道仅是因为排序，
finished all of this so you know there's
only because of the sequencing there's
只有少数几种情况让我们担心
only a limited number of kind of
scenarios we made me worried about for
崩溃好了，所以工作站崩溃了，崩溃了
the crash okay so the workstations
crashed its crashed you know for like to
令人兴奋的是，当控股公司锁定发生的第一件事时，让我们崩溃
be exciting let's crash while Holdings
locks the first thing that happens the
锁定服务器向其发送吊销请求，并且锁定服务器未获得任何响应
lock server sends it a revoke request
and the lock server gets no response all
没错，这就是开始触发任何事情的地方，没人问过
right that's what starts to trigger
anything where did nobody ever asked for
锁
the lock
基本上没人会注意到工作站崩溃了，所以让我们
basically nobody's ever going to notice
that the workstation crashed so let's
假设其他人想要工作站在其工作时拥有的一把锁
assume somebody else wanted one of the
locks that the workstation had while it
崩溃了，锁服务终止了，它永远也不会释放
was crashed and the lock service ended
revoke and it will never get a release
经过一定时间后从工作站返回
back from the workstation after a
certain amount of time has passed and it
事实证明，素馨花锁使用租赁的原因有很多，所以您知道
turns out frangipani locks use leases
for a number of reasons so you know
最少时间过后，锁定服务器将决定
after the least time has expired the
lock server will decide that the
工作站必须崩溃了，它将启动恢复以及那
workstation must have crashed and it
will initiate recovery and what that
真正的意思是告诉锁服务器将告诉另一个工作站
really means is telling a different
workstation the lock server will tell
其他一些实时工作站外观工作站似乎已崩溃
some other live workstation look
workstation one seems to have crashed
请阅读日志并重播其最近的所有操作，以确保
please go read it's log and replay all
of its recent operations to make sure
他们完成了，告诉我什么时候完成，只有锁服务器
they're complete and tell me when you're
done and only then the lock servers
将要释放锁，这样就可以了
going to release the locks so okay so
and and this is the point at which it
至关重要的是，日志要放在踏板上，因为其他工作站正在运行
was critical that the logs are in pedal
because some other workstation is going
检查崩溃工作站的登录踏板
to inspect the crash workstations log in
pedal
好吧，那么可能性是什么，那就是最糟糕的是您可能崩溃
all right so what are the possibilities
one is that the worst that you can crash
在它写回任何东西之前，所以这意味着另一个工作站
before it ever wrote anything back and
so that means this other work station
做恢复将查看崩溃工作站的此日志，看看也许
doing recovery will look at the crash
workstation this log see that maybe
里面什么也没有，什么也不做，然后释放锁
there's nothing in it at all and do
nothing and then release the locks the
现在举办的工作站最糟糕，您可能已经修改了所有内容
workstation held now the worst that you
may have modified all kinds of things in
它的缓存，但是如果它没有向他的日志区域写入任何内容，那么它
its cache but if it didn't write
anything to his log area then it
不可能写出在此期间修改过的任何块
couldn't possibly have written any of
the blocks that have modified during
这些操作正确，所以很好，我们将丢失最后的几个操作
these operations right and so well we
will have lost the last few operations
工作站所做的文件系统将与这一点保持一致
that the workstation did the file system
is going to be consistent with the point
在崩溃的工作站开始修改之前，
in time before that crashed workstation
started to modify anything because
显然，工作站甚至无法达到正在编写的位置
apparently the workstation never even
got to the point where it was writing
日志条目工作站的下一个可能性写了一些日志条目
log entries the next possibilities of
the workstation wrote some log entries
日志区域，在这种情况下，恢复工作站将向前扫描
the log area and in that case the
recovering workstation will scan forward
从日志开始到停止查看日志序列号
from the beginning of log until it's
stopped seeing the log sequence numbers
这就是日志必须在哪里安东和恢复
increasing that's the point of where's
the log must Anton and the recovering
工作站，我们将逐一介绍这些变更描述，
workstation we'll look at each of these
descriptions of a change and basically
播放变回花瓣的声音我会说哦，你知道有一定的障碍
play that change back into petal I'll
say oh you know there's certain block
数字和花瓣需要写入一些特定数据，这仅仅是
number and petal needs to have some
certain data written to it which is just
与崩溃的工作站在其自己的本地缓存中所做的相同的修改
the same modification that the crashed
workstation did in its own local cache
因此，在恢复工作站中，我们将仅考虑其中的每一个并重播每个
so the recovering workstation we'll just
consider each of these and replay each
崩溃的工作站将日志条目重新记录到花瓣中，完成后
of the crashed workstations log entries
back into petal and when it's done that
一直到崩溃的工作站日志的结尾，因为它存在于花瓣中
all the way to the end of a crashed
workstations log as it exists in petal
它会告诉锁服务器，锁服务器将释放崩溃的
it'll tell the lock server and the lock
server will release the crashed
工作站锁，这将使踏板具有最新的前缀
workstations locks and that will bring
the pedal up to date with some prefix of
崩溃工作站在崩溃之前完成的操作可能不是全部
the operations the crash workstation had
done before crashing maybe not all of
他们，因为也许它没有写出所有的日志，但恢复是
them because maybe it didn't write out
all of its log but the recovery were
季节不会在日志条目中重播任何内容
season
won't replay anything in a log entry
除非它在花瓣中具有完整的日志条目，所以您隐含地知道
unless it has the complete log entry in
petal and so you know implicitly that
意味着会有某种校验和安排或其他方式，所以
means there's gonna be some sort of
checksum arrangement or something so the
恢复工作站将知道啊哈，此日志条目已完成并且不喜欢
recovery work station will know aha this
log entry is complete and not like
部分编写的内容非常重要，因为这的全部重点是
partially written that's quite important
because the whole point of this is to
确保只有完整的操作可见，并且花瓣永不消失
make sure that only complete operations
are visible and petal and never never
永远不会进行部分操作，因此，对于
never a partial operation so it's also
important that all the rights for a
给定操作或组一起在日志中，以便在恢复时进行恢复
given operation or a group together in
the log so that on recovery the recovery
工作站可以拥有一项操作的所有权利，或者没有任何权利永远不会一半
workstation can do all of the rights for
an operation or none of them never half
他们好，所以这就是如果在日志被记录时发生崩溃的情况
of them ok so that's what happens if the
crash happens while the log is being
写回花瓣另一个有趣的可能性是
written back to petal a another
interesting possibility is that the
崩溃工作站在写入日志以及写入一些日志后崩溃
crash workstation crashed after writing
its log and also after writing some of
块本身返回，然后崩溃，然后掠过一些极端
the blocks back itself and then crashed
and then skimming over some extremely
重要的细节，我稍后会谈到，然后又会发生
important details which I'll get to in a
moment then what will happen is again
恢复工作站当然是工作站不知道的恢复
the recovery workstation of course the
recovery where station doesn't know
工作站崩溃的真正点是哦
really the point at which the
workstation crashed all it sees is oh
这是一些日志条目，恢复工作站将再次重放日志
here's some log entries and again the
recovery workstation will replay the log
以相同的方式或多或少发生了什么事，是的，即使
in the same way and more or less what's
going on is that yeah even if the
修改已经在花瓣中完成，我们正在重放相同的修改
modifications were already done in petal
we're replaying the same modifications
在这里，学生们正在玩同样的修改的恢复
here the recovery where students were
playing the same modifications it just
再次在同一位置写入相同的数据，大概并没有真正改变
writes the same data the same place
again and presumably not really changing
已经完成但如果崩溃的写入的值
the value for the writes that had
already been completed but if the crash
工作站没有行使其某些权利，那么其中一些权利是
workstation hadn't done some of its
rights then some of these rights were
不确定哪个会实际更改数据以完成所有操作
not sure which will actually change the
data to complete the operations all
对
right
实际上，事实并非如此，因为今天的问题已经解决
that's not actually as it turns out the
full story and today's question sets up
在特定情况下，需要增加一点复杂性
a particular scenario for which a little
bit of added complexity is necessary in
尤其是崩溃的工作站实际上已经获得的可能性
particular the possibility that the
crashed workstation had actually gotten
在崩溃之前经历了整个过程，实际上释放了一些
through this entire sequence before
crashing and in fact released some of
它的锁，所以它不是最后一个修改工作站的人
its locks or so that it wasn't the last
person the last workstation to modify a
特定的数据，所以举一个例子，如果我们有一些
particular piece of data so an example
of this is what happens if we have some
工作站并执行说一个删除文件，它删除一个文件说文件F，然后
workstation and it executes say a delete
file it deletes a file say a file F and
目录D，然后有其他工作站在删除之后
directory D and then there's some other
workstation which after this delete
创建一个具有相同名称的新文件，但是现在它是一个不同的文件
creates a new file with the same name
but of course it's a different file now
所以工作站1对不起，两个工作站以后创建相同
so workstation 1 I'm sorry
workstation two later create create same
文件具有相同的文件名，然后在该工作站1崩溃后，我们将
file same file name and then after that
workstation 1 crashes so we're going to
需要您对工作站的日志进行恢复，因此在这一点上
need you to do recovery on workstation
ones log and so at this point in time
你知道也许有第三台工作站在做恢复
you know maybe there's a third
workstation doing the recovery
所以现在工作站3正在恢复
so now workstation 3 is doing a recover
在工作站的日志上，因此顺序显示工作站1删除了文件或
on workstation ones log so the sequence
says workstation 1 deleted a file or
工作站2创建了一个文件，或者工作站3进行了恢复，您可能知道
station 2 created a file or station 3
does recovery well you know could be
该删除仍在工作站的日志中，因此您可能知道工作站2
that this delete is still in workstation
ones log so workstation two may you know
或站1即将崩溃或站3将查看其日志
or station 1 crash just going to go or
station 3 is going to look at its log
这将重放工作站日志中的所有更新
that's going to replay all
all the updates in workstation ones log
此删除可能为此删除的更新
this delete may the updates for this
delete the entry for this delete may
仍然在工作站的日志中，所以除非我们做一些聪明的事
工作站3将删除此文件，您知道，因为这
workstation 3 is going to delete this
file you know because this this
该操作从目录中删除了相关条目
因此实际上是删除删除该文件，因为它是另一个文件
thus actually erasing deleting this file
that's it's a different file that
工作站2之后创建的，所以这是完全错误的
想知道我们要怎么来吗想知道马站一删
want you know the how come we want is
you know horse station one deleted a
该文件应删除，但如果文件名不应该是一个新文件
file that file should be deleted but a
new file that if her name should not be
删除只是因为它在重启cuz中崩溃，此创建发生在
deleted just because it was a crash in a
restart cuz this create happen after
删除所有权限，这样我们就不能在没有日志的情况下重播工作站日志
delete all right so we cannot just
replay workstation ones log without
进一步考虑，因为它可能实际上可能是工作站中的日志条目
further thought because it may it may
essentially a log entry in workstations
在恢复过程中播放一本日志时，它可能已过时
one log may be out of date by the time
it's we played during recovery some
其他工作站可能已经修改了相同的数据和其他方式
other workstation may have modified the
same data and some other way
随后，因此我们不能盲目地重播日志条目，所以这是
subsequently so we can't blindly replay
the log entries and so this is this is
这是今天的问题，素馨花解决这个问题的方法是通过联系
this is today's question and the way
frangipani solves this is by associating
版本号以及存储在踏板中的文件系统中的所有数据
并且还将相同的版本号与每个更新相关联
and also associating the same version
number with every update that's
在日志中进行了说明，因此每个日志条目在刚开始的时候我都没有
你会说在踏板上我只会在踏板上说每个元数据
you know say in pedal I'll just say in
pedal every piece of metadata every
索引每一个类似于目录内容的数据
inode every every piece of data that's
like the contents of a directory for
示例存储的每个数据元数据块和踏板都有一个版本号
example every block of data metadata in
stored and pedal has a version number
当工作站需要先修改踏板中的元数据时
when a workstation needs to modify a
piece of metadata in pedal it first
从踏板读取该元数据到其内存中，然后查看现有的
reads that metadata from pedal into its
memory and then looks at the existing
的版本，然后在创建日志文件时
version of
and then when it's creating the log file
描述其修改后，会将现有版本号加一个
describing its modification it puts the
existing version number plus one into
日志条目，然后将其放入（如果确实有机会将数据写回）
the log entry and then when it in if it
does get a chance to write the data back
它将使用新增加的版本号写回数据，因此如果超过
it'll write the data back with the new
increased version number so if over
工作站尚未崩溃，是否崩溃，或者是否确实能写回一些数据
station hasn't crashed and it did or if
it did manage to write some data back
在崩溃之前，版本号已存储在花瓣中
before it crashed then the version
number has stored in petal for the
受影响的元数据将至少与版本号一样高或更高
effected metadata it will be at least as
high or higher than the version numbers
存储在日志条目中的其他工作站将会更高
stored in the log entry there will be
higher some other workstations
随后进行了修改，所以这里实际发生的是
subsequently modified so what will
actually happen here is that the what
我们将看到的工作站3是删除一个工作站的日志条目
workstation 3 we'll see is that the log
entry for workstations one delete
操作将在日志条目中存储一个特定的版本号，
operation will have a particular version
number stored in the log entry that
比方说，与对目录的修改相关联的日志条目
associated with the modification to the
directory let's say and the log entry
会说好目录的版本号和新的版本号
will say well the version number for the
directory and the new version number
由此日志条目创建的版本号为3的工作站
created by this log entry is version
number three in order for workstation
两个随后更改实际上在之前添加文件应用程序的目录
two to subsequently change the directory
that is to add a file app in fact before
它使工作站崩溃了，必须放弃该目录中的锁定，并且
it crashed the workstation one must have
given up the lock in the directory and
这可能就是为什么日志条目甚至存在于踏板中的原因，因此工作站1必须
that's probably why the log entry even
exists in pedal so workstation 1 must
显然已经放弃了锁，工作站两个拿到了锁并读取了
have given up the lock apparently
workstation two got the lock and read
该目录的当前元数据显示版本号为3
the current metadata for the directory
saw that the version number was three
现在，当两个工作站写入此数据时，它将设置版本号或
now and when workstation two writes this
data it will set the version number or
peddle中的目录为4 ok，因此这意味着该日志条目
the directory in peddle to be 4 ok so
the that means the log entry for this
删除操作现在将具有版本号3，
delete operation is going to have
version number 3 in it now when the
最差代理3上的恢复软件会重播它查看的工作站日志
recovery software on worst agent 3
replays workstation ones log it looks at
首先是版本号，所以它将查看日志条目的版本号
the version numbers first so it'll look
at the version number the log entry
它会通过查看块中的版本号来读取该块
it'll read the block from
look at the version number in the block
并且如果踏板中的块中的版本号大于或等于
and if the version number in the block
in pedal is greater than or equal to the
恢复软件将忽略的日志条目中的版本号
version number in the log entry the
recovery software will simply ignore
在日志条目中进行更新，而不是这样做，因为显然该块已经
that update in the log entry and not do
it because clearly the block had already
由崩溃工作站写回，然后可能随后
been written back by the crash
workstation and then maybe subsequently
由其他工作站修改，因此重播实际上是基于
modified by other workstations so the
replay is actually selectively based on
重放的此版本号仅是恢复
this version number that replay it's a
recovery only writes only
如果日志中的权限实际上是较新的，则重放在日志中是正确的
replays are right in the log if that
right is actually newer right in the log
条目比已存储在peddle中的数据更新，因此一种
entry is newer than the data that's
already stored in peddle so one sort of
这里令人烦恼的问题可能是第三工作站正在运行
irritating question here maybe is that
workstation three is running this
恢复软件，而其他工作站仍在读取和
recovery software while other
workstations are still reading and
主动在文件系统中写入内容并具有锁定，并且知道要兜售什么
writing in the file system actively and
have locks and knows what to peddle so
重播将在我们不知道的位置继续进行
the replay it's gonna go on while we're
station to which that doesn't know
关于恢复的任何信息仍然处于活动状态，实际上两个工作站可能具有
anything about the recovery still active
and indeed workstation two may have the
恢复时锁定此目录，以便恢复
lock for this directory
while recoveries going on so recovery
可能正在扫描日志，您无需读取或写入此目录数据
may be scanning the log and you no need
to read or write this directories data
在工作站两个仍在锁定此数据时，问题是
in pedal while workstation two still has
the lock on this data the question is
您怎么知道我们如何像一种可能
how you know how do we sort this out
like one possibility which actually
原来不起作用的是恢复软件首先获取了
turns out not to work is for the
recovery software to first acquire the
重放前锁定需要在花瓣上查看的任何内容
lock on anything that it needs to look
at in petal before while it's replaying
日志，您知道为什么不起作用的一个好原因是它
the log and the the you know one good
reason why that doesn't work is that it
可能是由于
could be that we're running recovery
after a system-wide power failure for
例子，所有关于谁拥有什么锁的知识都丢失了，因此我们
example in which all knowledge of who
had what locks is lost and therefore we
无法编写恢复软件以参与锁定
cannot write the recovery software to
sort of participate in the locking
协议，因为您了解锁定的所有知识
protocol because
you know all knowledge of what's locked
我的未锁定插槽可能在电源故障中丢失了
my slot not locked may have been lost in
the power failure
嗯，但是幸运的是，恢复软件可以继续
um but luckily it turns out that the
recovery software can just go ahead and
读取或写入踏板中的块，而不必担心抱歉的读取或写入数据
read or write blocks in pedal without
worrying about sorry read or write data
在踏板上而不用担心锁，原因是如果
in pedal without worrying at all about
locks and the reason is that if the
您知道的恢复软件恢复软件要重播此日志条目
recovery software you know the recovery
software wants to replay this log entry
并可能会修改与此目录关联的数据
and possibly modify the data associated
with this directory it just goes ahead
并立即从踏板上读取目录的所有内容
and reads whatever's there for the
directory out of pedal right now and
实际上只有两种情况：崩溃工作站放弃了它
there's really only two cases either the
crash workstation one had given up its
锁或没有锁，如果没有放弃此锁，那么没有其他人可以拥有
lock or it hadn't if it hadn't given up
this lock then nobody else can have a
目录已锁定，因此如果放弃了锁定就没有问题
directory locked and so there's no
problem if it had given up its lock then
在我放弃它的锁之前，它必须先写出它的数据
before I gave it up its lock it must
have written that it's data for the
目录返回到踏板，这意味着版本号存储在踏板中
directory back to pedal and that means
that the version number stored in pedal
必须至少与崩溃的工作站日志中的版本号一样高
must be at least as high as the version
number in the crashed workstations log
条目，因此恢复软件比较日志条目的版本
entry and therefore when recovery
software compares the log entry version
编号以及数据和踏板的版本号，它将看到日志
number with the version number of the
data and pedal it'll see that the log
条目版本号不高，因此我们不会播放日志条目，因此
entry version number is not higher and
therefore won't we play the log entry so
是的，恢复软件将无需持有锁即可读取该块
yeah the recovery software will have
read the block without holding the lock
但它不会修改它，因为如果锁定已释放，则该版本
but it's not going to modify it because
if the locked was released the version
数字将足够高，以表明日志条目已经属于
number will be high enough to show that
the log entry had already been sort of
在崩溃的工作站崩溃之前处理踏板没有，所以没有
processing to pedal before the crashed
workstation crashed no so there's no
锁定问题好吧，这是我已经克服了
locking issue alright this is the I've
gone over that kind of main guts of what
踏板由Nam决定，它的缓存一致性，分布式事务和
pedal is up to Nam it's cache coherence
it's distributed transactions and it's
分布式崩溃恢复其他需要考虑的是本文
distributed crash recovery the other
things to think about are the the paper
谈到性能，20多年后实际上很难
talks a bit about performance it's
actually very hard after over 20 years
解释绩效数字，因为他们将绩效数字标记在
to interpret performance numbers because
they brand their performance numbers on
与环境完全不同的硬件
very different Hardware in a very
different environment from
您今天看到的大概是他们显示的效果数字，或者
you see today roughly speaking the
performance numbers they show or that as
您基本上会增加越来越多的友谊和工作站
you add more and more friendship and
work stations the system basically
不会变慢，即使每个新工作站都在积极运行
doesn't get slower that is each new
workstation even if it's actively doing
文件系统操作不会降低现有工作站的速度
file system operations doesn't slow down
the existing workstation so in that
至少在应用程序状态下感知您所知道的系统，看看系统
sense the system you know at least for
the application state look at the system
给他们合理的可扩展性，他们可以添加更多的工作站而无需
was giving them reasonable scalability
they could add more workstations without
减慢现有用户向后看的速度
slowing existing users down looking
backwards
尽管素馨花充满了非常有趣的技术，但值得
although frangipani is full of like very
interesting techniques that are worth
记住它并没有太大影响
remembering it didn't have too much
influence in on how on the evolution of
存储系统的部分原因是针对的环境
storage systems part of the reason is
that the environment for which is aimed
那是坐在工作站前的小型工作组
that is small workgroups
people sitting in front of workstations
在他们的办公桌上并共享文件，使环境很好地存在于某些环境中
on their desks and sharing files that
environment well it still exists in some
操作实际上不在分布式存储中的位置
places isn't really where the action is
in distributed storage the action the
实际行动被转移到大数据中心或大网站大数据中
real action is moved into sort of big
data center or big websites big data
计算，您首先在那个世界知道文件系统
computations and there you know in that
world first of all the file system
与像人一样的数据库相比，界面只是不是很有用
interface just isn't very useful
compared to databases like people really
像大型网站世界中的交易一样，但它们只需要很小的交易
like transactions in the big website
world but they need them for very small
数据项您将存储在数据库而不是数据库中的数据类型
items of data the kind of data that you
would store in a database rather than
您自然会存储在文件系统中的那种数据，以便您
the kind of data that would you would
naturally store in a file system so you
知道其中一些技术可能会让您在现代中看到它的回声
know some of this technology might sort
of you can see echoes of it in modern
系统，但通常采用某种数据库的形式，另一种则是
systems but it usually takes the form of
some database the other big kind of
将其存储在那里，根据大数据的需要存储大文件
storage this out there is storing big
files as needed for big data
像MapReduce和GFS这样的计算在某种程度上看起来是
computations like MapReduce and indeed
GFS is a you know to some extent looks
就像文件系统一样，是您想要MapReduce使用的存储系统
like a file system and is the kind of
storage system you want for MapReduce
但是对于GFS和大数据计算，素馨
but for GFS and for big data
computations frangipane ease you know
专注于本地缓存和工作站，并且非常关注
focus on local caching and workstations
and very close attention to
缓存的一致性和锁定对于您知道
cache coherence and locking it's just
not very useful you know for both the
数据读写通常缓存根本没有用
data read and write
typically caching is not useful at all
对，如果您正在读取十亿兆字节的数据，
right if you're reading through ten
terabytes of data it's really
几乎适得其反，以至于无法缓存它，所以素馨花的很多重点都在整理中
counterproductive almost to cache it so
a lot of the focus in frangipani is sort
时间流逝了一点点，它在某些情况下仍然有用，但是
of time is pass it by a little bit it's
still useful in some situations but it's
不是人们在为所有人设计新系统时真正考虑的问题
not what people are really thinking
about in designing new systems for all
对的就是这样
right that is it